You better resign.
你最好辭職
Hand over your severance pay and I'll make all this disappear.
交出你的離職金，我就處理掉這件事
Dr. Seishiro Tokai.
渡海征司郎醫生
Forcing doctors to resign and taking their money. The devil himself.
迫使同事辭職並詐取錢財 人稱“手術室惡魔”
And now he's my mentor.
成了我的指導前輩
I am working as an intern here.
我擔任實習醫生的醫院
At Tojo University Hospital.
是東城大學附屬醫院
Here, our cardiac surgeon, Professor Saeki,
這裡的心臟外科佐伯教授
performs surgeries without stopping the heart with his Saeki Method.
以其佐伯式執刀手法 可在心臟不暫停的情況下進行手術
It's a procedure not seen anywhere else in the world.
這是全世界獨一無二的高難度技術
He and Dr. Nishizaki of Teika University are in fierce competition of Impact Factor
他和帝華大學的西崎教授 為了爭奪理事長的位置
for the position of Chairman.
正在激烈較勁
Together with his pupil, Dr. Takashina,
西崎帶領子弟兵高階醫生
he brought a new surgical tool, the Snipe.
合力引進一款新型手術工具“醫狙”
There is no longer a need for the Hand of God.
再也不需要什麼神之手了
Japan's very first Snipe operation
並且，日本首例使用醫狙的手術
was performed on my patient.
在我負責的病人身上進行
The operation was a success
手術很成功
and proved the Snipe's ability to replace the need for human hands.
也證明了醫狙的功能 足以取代人的雙手
Soon after, the patient took a turn for the worse.
但不久後，病患的情況急轉直下
Dr. Takashina found himself in a hopeless situation.
高階醫生陷入無計可施的困境
Damn it!
可惡！
That's when Dr. Tokai arrived.
這時渡海醫生出現了
I'm begging you. Help this woman. Please!
求求你了，救救這位婦女，拜託你！
But Dr. Tokai doesn't help out others for free.
但渡海醫生不會做白工
One hundred million.
一億日圓
Until you pay me off,
在你付清之前
you're stuck here working for me.
你得在這裡替我做牛做馬一輩子
If Dr. Tokai hadn't been there,
要是沒有渡海醫生
Ms. Minagawa would have died.
皆川女士早就沒命了
There was nothing I could do.
而我卻無能為力
I could have caused
我本來可能
my own patient's death.
斷送了自己病患的生命
Who cares about the Snipe?
誰在乎什麼醫狙啊？ 根本只是小孩的玩具
After the Snipe operation,
使用醫狙進行手術之後
Dr. Takashina's standing at Tojo
高階醫生在東城醫院裡的地位
took a turn for the worse.
更是一落千丈
If the patient had died,
如果病患就那樣死了
our image would have been spoiled forever.
本院的形象一定會毀於一旦
What did he even come here for? The trouble he caused…
到底來這裡幹嘛？ 真會給我們找麻煩…
He's not a doctor. Just a lowly Snipe salesman.
算了，他根本稱不上醫生 只是不入流的醫狙推銷員
-You nailed it. -Right?
-說得對 -沒錯
Out of my way.
礙事
Oh, excuse me.
抱歉
Keep it down. I can't sleep.
小聲一點，我睡不著
Right…
好…
I assume you're all able to perform mitral surgery, right?
各位醫生應該都會做二尖瓣手術吧？
That salesman did it and succeeded.
那位推銷員可是勉強完成了
What are you planning?
你在盤算什麼？
You want me to thank you?
想讓我感謝你嗎？
Let me sleep.
別吵我睡覺
Ms. Minagawa underwent the procedure, but the paper's publication was delayed.
皆川女士進行的醫狙手術 相關的論文發表延遲了
This also had a large influence in the fight for Impact Factor.
這對影響因子的爭奪戰帶來重大影響
Because of Dr. Takashina,
因為高階醫生
the Impact Factor we were hoping for is out the window.
本來有機會到手的影響因子也泡湯了
Don't worry.
別擔心
Besides, Japan's first Snipe surgery was a success.
而且，日本的首例醫狙手術成功了
We'll complete more cases in Japan
今後我們還會完成更多案例
and submit a paper concerning its high success rate.
再根據其高成功率提交論文
Right.
也是
We have the election to think about as well,
我們還要想想理事長選舉
so this will all work in our favor.
整體局勢應該會對我們有利
The most important thing now
眼下最重要的
is our Impact Factor.
就是我們的影響因子
A doctor's world is so mysterious.
醫生的世界真是高深莫測
Hmm?
什麼？
From the patient's perspective, a good doctor is one who can cure them.
從病患的角度來看 能治好自己的醫生就是好醫生
But from your side,
但對醫生來說
a good doctor is one who can write a good paper.
寫得出論文的才算良醫
Why did you choose this restaurant?
你為什麼選這家餐廳？
Because it has a Michelin star.
因為這是米其林等級的
It's the same for us.
對我們來說是一樣的道理
This restaurant's value is decided by one man's opinion.
這家店的價值取決於他人所定的標準
It's a stressful reality, but it's what everyone wants.
很沉重的事實，但人人卻又無比渴求
It must seem foolish from the outside.
從旁觀者的角度來看很愚蠢吧
Regardless,
即便如此
all doctors strive for Impact Factor,
所有醫生還是拼了命爭取影響因子
fighting for it in a blind rage.
不惜為此殺紅了眼
It decides a doctor's worth. Their future.
因為它決定了醫生的價值與未來
In fact, it determines their entire life.
實際上，甚至可以說 決定他們全部的人生
Is that also true for the election for Chairman?
理事長選舉的結果也是，對嗎？
You scared me.
嚇我一跳
-Please excuse me. -It's okay.
-不好意思 -沒關係
Here are the items for today's duty.
這是今天值班的交辦事項
-Thank you. -Forgive me.
-謝謝 -真的很抱歉
You're still here practicing.
你還在練習啊？
"Practice makes perfect."
“熟能生巧”嘛
Pelé's words.
比利的名言
Pelé?
比利？
Yes, the soccer star.
對啊，足球巨星
-That's Pelé. -Okay.
-他就是比利 -這樣啊
-I see. -Sorry.
-我知道了 -不好意思
No, forgive me.
我才不好意思
It was frustrating.
真的很洩氣
Not being able to do anything back there.
在手術室時什麼都做不到
I have to prove myself to Dr. Tokai.
我一定要向渡海醫生證明自己
I'll do my best to become fully qualified too.
我也會竭盡所能，當一個稱職的護士
-Good night.
-那晚安了 -晚安
Okay.
繼續吧
Hello.
你好
Emergency transport from Sakuranomiya Hospital.
有一位從櫻宮醫院 緊急轉院過來的患者
Male, sixties. Abdominal aortic aneurysm about to rupture.
60多歲的男性 腹主動脈瘤快破裂了
We believe he needs emergency surgery.
應該需要做緊急手術
He's a mitral valve surgery patient, scheduled for next month.
他有心臟二尖瓣的問題 原定下個月動手術
-We're taking him to OR one. -Understood.
-送到第一手術室 -知道了
I'll tell Dr. Tokai.
我會通知渡海醫生
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
-The cardiac surgeon has been contacted. -Take him in.
-已經聯絡心臟外科醫生了 -送他進去
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Honey! Hang in there!
老公，撐著點
-We'll take over. -Thank you.
-交給我吧 -謝謝
Please, no.
拜託你撐住
Where are you?
到底跑去哪裡了？
-Thank you.
-拜託了 -謝謝
-One, two, three. -I'm taking off your glasses.
-一、二、三 -幫您拿下眼鏡
Damn it!
可惡
Dr. Tokai isn't here. I have to do it myself.
渡海醫生不在，我只能靠自己了
Calm down. I know the procedure.
冷靜，我知道流程
I've practiced countless times.
已經練習過無數次了
Remove the renal vein if bleeding is controlled.
如果出血控制住，把腎靜脈剝離
Dislocate below the renal artery.
阻斷腎動脈下端
Then I'll have to block the abdominal aorta.
然後阻斷腹主動脈
And then… next…
接下來是…
Impossible.
做不到
I can't do it.
我就是做不到
Spatula.
壓板
-Gauze. -What are you doing?
-紗布 -你怎麼還愣在那裡？
-Bring the gauze. -Sorry.
-把紗布拿過來 -抱歉
Hurry up.
快點
Yes, sir!
是
OPERATION IN PROGRESS
（手術中）
Um, they're operating at this hour?
怎麼會在這個時間動手術？
There was an emergency patient.
剛剛收治一名急診病患
Dr. Tokai is operating.
由渡海醫生執刀
-Suction. -Okay.
-抽吸 -好的
-Don't mess up. -Sorry.
-別搞砸了 -是，抱歉
-Deeper. -Yes, sorry.
-深一點 -好的
Metz.
手術剪
Right prosthesis done. Next is left.
右邊人工血管好了，現在換左邊
-Four-zero. -Okay.
-4-0縫線 -好
-I'm done. -What?
-我做完了 -什麼？
Doctor, the left stitches…
渡海醫生，左邊的縫合…
Do it yourself.
你自己來
-What? -"Practice makes perfect."
-什麼？ -“熟能生巧”
You want to be Pelé, right?
你不是想向比利看齊嗎？
-I… -An old athlete like that…
-我… -那麼老的運動員…
-You don't know him, do you? -I, well…
-你應該不認識吧？ -我，那個…
-It's just… -Do it.
-只是… -動手啊
-You want to prove yourself, right? -It's not like that.
-你不是想證明自己嗎？ -不是的
-Dr. Sera… -Hey, intern. Are you okay?
-世良醫生… -實習的，你行不行？
Those are my orders. Any problem?
是我的指令，有問題嗎？
No… Sorry.
沒有，抱歉
Okay.
是
Calm down.
冷靜
They're only stitches.
只是縫合而已
I've practiced for this.
我已經練習過了
Gauze!
紗布！
Gauze! If we don't stop the bleeding, she'll die!
不能止血的話，患者就死定了
Okay.
好了
Metz, please.
請給我手術剪
Here.
這裡
I did it.
完成了
-Dr. Tokai. -Forceps out.
-渡海醫生 -鬆開止血鉗
Okay.
是
-Bring more gauze. -Right.
-再多拿點紗布來 -是
Give me that.
給我
You've killed a person.
你剛剛害死一個人了
No, sorry.
抱歉
You've killed two.
是第二個了
Get out.
礙事
How dare you make light of a patient's life.
你把患者的生命當成什麼了
Oh, you were watching?
你看到了嗎？
Then why not do it yourself?
那你怎麼不自己來動手術？
I've got my training report.
這是實習報告
-Here it is. -Thank you.
-給您 -謝謝
REPORT FORMS
（各類申請書）
"Training relocation request form…"
“更換實習地點申請書”…
TRAINING RELOCATION REQUEST FORM
（更換實習地點申請書）
Dr. Sera!
世良醫生
Come with me, please.
可以跟我來一趟嗎？
Mr. Koyama is trying to leave the hospital.
小山先生要求出院
Coming.
來了
-Listen to me! -Excuse me.
-聽我的話嘛！ -打擾了
Doctor. My husband won't listen and he says he's leaving.
醫生，我老公堅持要出院 根本不聽勸
I'm losing business deals left and right because I collapsed.
因為我倒下，已經流失很多生意
-If I stay here, my factory will go under. -Please relax.
-再繼續待著，我的工廠就要倒閉了 -請您冷靜點
-Please, I won't overdo it. -You leaving is overdoing it.
-沒事的，我不會逞強 -您現在出院就是逞強
They told me my something-something valve is no good,
他們說我的什麼瓣膜出問題
but I'm telling you, I'm totally fine.
但我現在明明好得很
That's a separate issue.
那是另一個部分的問題
You still need to undergo surgery to fix the underlying issue.
您還需要再做一次手術才能根治
-As soon as possible. -I don't have time for surgery.
-越快越好 -我根本沒時間動手術
I have deadlines coming up. Let me out of here.
交期就要到了，請讓我出院吧
-Sir, you see… -Go ahead.
-先生，您… -那就出院吧
-I can go? -Dr. Tokai…
-可以嗎？ -渡海醫生…
If you leave now, you'll die before you make any deadlines.
不過如果您現在就出院的話 交期還沒到就會掛了
And even if you decide to stay here,
就算您決定留下來
you'll be dead in a month anyway.
一個月後還是會死
Isn't there something we can do? Won't surgery fix it?
那該怎麼辦？動手術不能治好嗎？
-We won't know unless we try. -Unless you try?
-要試試看才知道 -試試看？
Surgery is a gamble.
手術就像賭博
In the end, it's a 50-50 chance.
成敗機率各半
Heads or tails, you live or…
不是正面就是反面，不是活著就是…
you die.
死掉
We won't know unless we try.
只有嘗試了才知道
And if you still want to leave,
如果您還是堅持出院的話
tell this guy.
就告訴這傢伙一聲
We're scheduled to perform aortic valve surgery this weekend.
所以預定這週末進行主動脈瓣手術
That concludes the case report. Any questions?
以上就是病例報告 還有其他問題嗎？
-If not… -Excuse me.
-沒有的話就… -不好意思
What is it?
什麼事？
It's about Mr. Koyama, the emergency patient in Room 403…
是關於403號病房的 急診病患小山先生…
The patient who needs mitral valve surgery?
是那位需要做二尖瓣手術的患者吧？
Yes.
對
I just got word from the family that they wish to undergo surgery.
剛剛家屬已經說願意動手術
You are aware that Dr. Saeki's schedule is packed for the next two months.
佐伯教授的手術計畫 已經排到兩個月後了
We'll look into scheduling a date.
我們再看看怎麼安排時間
Thank you.
謝謝
And when will that date be decided?
什麼時候能決定日期？
This patient might die tomorrow and you can't make time for him?
這個病患可能明天就死了 你居然無法挪出時間？
Why not operate right away, Dr. Saeki?
佐伯教授 為什麼不能立刻替他動手術？
Don't be rude. We have many similar patients.
別那麼無禮，這類病患多得是
We can't play favorites.
我們不能給特殊待遇
But as a hospital, we simply can't afford to allow our patients to die.
但作為醫院 也不能對病人見死不救吧？
This is a problem.
真是麻煩
Why not leave the patient with me?
不如把病患交給我吧？
-With you? -I would like to perform Snipe surgery.
-交給你？ -我想用醫狙來動手術
-Snipe surgery? -That last patient almost died.
-用醫狙動手術？ -患者只剩下半條命
You've hardly used it. How could you do it?
你根本還不熟練，談什麼做手術
Who will take responsibility this time?
這次出問題誰要負責？
I will… take responsibility.
責任由我來付
Ms. Minagawa's condition changed rapidly.
皆川女士當時的病況的確急速惡化
But that was a problem separate from the mitral valve.
但那是出自於跟二尖瓣無關的問題
The Snipe showed no issues.
醫狙本身沒有問題
Regardless, you still endangered the patient.
無論如何 你還是危害了病患的生命安全
Forgive me for talking back,
恕我直言
but her condition wouldn't allow for the Saeki method either.
患者當時的狀況 也無法接受佐伯式手術
Ms. Minagawa's life was saved,
皆川女士最後能撿回一命
thanks to the Snipe.
不就是醫狙的功勞嗎？
And she's not the only one.
而且不光是她
By using the Snipe,
只要會操作醫狙
anyone can perform mitral valve surgery.
誰都能夠做二尖瓣置換手術
We can save more lives.
會有更多人得救
Change the rules if necessary.
必要的時刻就改變規則吧
Let's leave our petty criticisms behind
別再為反對而反對
and work together.
大家通力合作吧
Understood.
知道了
Go ahead.
就這麼辦吧
Let us look past the last time.
上次的事既往不咎
Let's use the Snipe. For the patient's sake.
為了救治患者，就用醫狙動手術吧
Thank you. I'll get started right away.
謝謝，我會立刻去安排…
There is just one condition.
但我有個條件
Condition?
條件？
We let someone else perform the surgery.
由其他醫生來負責手術
You will not be allowed in the operating room either.
你甚至不准進入手術室
What is your objective?
這是什麼意思？
I believe you mentioned before
你剛才不是說
that with the Snipe, anyone can perform mitral valve surgery.
只要會操作醫狙 人人都能做二尖瓣置換手術
So there should be no problem in having our doctors give it a try.
這樣的話 其他醫生來操作應該也沒問題
That is true, but…
確實如此，但…
If your dream is realized,
如果你的理想成真
and the Snipe becomes the standard for Japanese surgery,
醫狙成為日本手術的標準器具
do you plan to be there to watch each one?
到那時你準備親自監督所有手術嗎？
In other words,
換句話說
this next surgery is your dream coming true.
接下來的這次手術可以實現你的夢想
There's still time to back out if you're uncertain.
如果猶豫的話，還有時間放棄
Very well. I believe in the Snipe.
那好吧，我對醫狙有信心
Then it's decided.
就這麼定了
Now, who shall perform the surgery?
那該派誰負責手術呢？
Hey, what are you doing?
你做什麼？
Right. Let's have him do it.
這樣啊，那就由他來做吧
You want to ask Sera?
您要交給世良醫生？
-He's just an intern. -You said anyone can use it.
-但他只是實習醫生 -是你說誰用都行的
Do you want to take back what you just said?
你想收回先前的話嗎？
I said it can be used by any surgeon.
我是指外科醫生都會用醫狙
Interns are not surgeons.
實習醫生還算不上外科醫生
Please select someone with experience.
至少請安排一個有經驗的醫生
I was being hypothetical.
說得很有道理
We'll leave the operation staff to Dr. Kurosaki.
那就請黑崎醫生來安排手術人員
-Understood. -Dr. Takashina,
-明白 -高階醫生
get the patient's consent for Snipe surgery.
你去跟患者取得手術同意
-Understood. -Do your best.
-好的 -盡力去做吧
I seriously thought it would be Sera.
我還真的以為要讓世良負責呢
Cut it out. It was just the professor joking around.
別鬧了，教授只是開玩笑
I would have been happy even if it were a joke.
換成我，就算是笑話我也高興
It seems like the professor really likes you.
看來教授真的很喜歡你
-Sera. -Yes?
-世良 -是的？
Can I talk to you?
可以跟你聊兩句嗎？
Of course.
好的
Mr. Koyama was unwilling to undergo Snipe surgery.
小山先生不接受用醫狙動手術
Isn't there some way we can see Dr. Saeki?
沒辦法請佐伯醫生來做手術嗎？
The doctor's schedule is full.
佐伯醫生的日程排滿了
So you're telling me you want me to be a guinea pig
所以你的意思是 要我當那個什麼醫狙玩意的
for that Snipe thing?
白老鼠嗎？
That's not what we mean.
我不是那個意思
Doctor.
醫生
I've brought our coordinator to explain things in further detail.
我們安排了協調員來詳細跟您解釋
Listen to her. Please come in.
由她跟您說明吧，請進
Nice to meet you. My name is Kinoshita, I'm a clinical trial coordinator.
幸會，我是臨床協調員木下
-But why? -She's an outstanding coordinator.
-為什麼？ -這位協調員非常優秀
I'll do my best to provide the information you need
我會盡可能提供你所需的資訊
to put your worries to rest.
讓你放心接受手術
Let me start by explaining the situation.
那麼我要開始說明手術的狀況了
The Snipe is still in clinical trial.
醫狙器械目前仍在臨床試驗階段
The coordinator works with the developer in America,
協調員跟美國開發商
Tojo University's testing facilities,
試驗場所東城大學
and the patients themselves.
以及病患本身合作
Research funds are given
進行臨床試驗的東城大學
by the developer to Tojo University,
會收到開發商提撥的研究費
as well as to the accepting patient.
參與試驗的病患也會收到一筆錢
This is called the "burden reduction fee."
名目是“減輕負擔費”
Please submit it promptly.
請收下
I hear you are in need of urgent care.
聽說您亟需照顧
Three million yen?
三百萬日圓？
Given to the patient by that coordinator who comes here often.
是常來我們醫院的那個協調員給的
She lives up to her shrewd reputation.
她果然名不虛傳
So that means the Snipe surgery is a go, right?
所以確定要用醫狙動手術了吧？
Pardon me. I brought a souvenir.
打擾了，我帶了禮物過來
Oh, no. Did we get the same thing?
糟糕，我們買了一樣的東西嗎？
Daifuku from Mizuho? Don't mind if I do.
是瑞穗的大福嗎？我不介意收下
You've heard of them, have you?
原來您也知道
One of Tokyo's best bean daifuku shops.
這是東京的三大豆大福名店之一
About Mr. Koyama…
關於小山先生…
It seems he has accepted the Snipe surgery.
他好像同意做醫狙手術了
It is my duty to ensure all parties profit from the situation.
確保各方利益是我的職責
I was able to negotiate twenty million
我跟公司商量好，爭取到兩千萬日圓
for your team's participation in the trial.
給您的團隊參與試驗
That should benefit you as well, I think.
教授您應該也能得好處
That is true.
的確是
But it also means you'll be doing Dr. Nishizaki from Teika a favor as well.
但這表示你也做了人情 給帝華大學的西崎教授
When the results of the Snipe surgery are published,
等到醫狙手術的成果發表論文
Dr. Nishizaki, being in charge of the research,
身為這項研究的負責人西崎教授
will see his Impact Factor grow significantly.
他的影響因子將會大幅提升
I'm sure it will also gain him
我相信這也會為他
many votes in the election for Chairman.
在理事長選舉贏得許多票吧
Yes, but if research continues without positive results,
話是沒錯，如果試驗始終沒有成果
Tojo will continue to get research funding.
東城大學就會一直收到 臨床試驗的經費
One man's failure
失之東隅
is another man's success.
收之桑榆啊
Be it Impact Factor or money.
無論是影響因子或是金錢都一樣
And I…
而我…
enjoy the fruits of their labor.
喜歡坐享其成
That's all.
僅此而已
I do have my doubts,
我多少有點猶豫
but it sounds like this is the only way.
但似乎只有這個辦法了
Thanks to you, I'm finally ready.
多虧你，我準備好了
Dear…
老公…
It's fine. Let's stay positive.
沒事的，要保持樂觀
I get free surgery and even reward money.
除了免費做手術，我還拿到報酬
I can pay off my debts.
可以用這筆錢來還債
What could be better?
還有比這更好的事嗎？
Even so…
話雖如此…
We'll give you full support until the operation.
手術之前，我們會給予完善的支持
Please be at ease.
請放心
Excuse me. I'll feel your abdomen.
不好意思，我要觸診一下腹部
Pardon me.
不好意思
You've killed a person.
你剛剛害死一個人了
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
Sorry.
抱歉
TRAINING RELOCATION REQUEST FORM MASASHI SERA
（更換實習醫院申請書）
Sera. Come here, please.
世良，過來一下
Coming.
是
We received Mr. Koyama's consent
小山先生已經同意做手術
and selected the operation staff.
手術成員也挑選好了
I will now announce the staff.
我現在要公布成員
Operating surgeon, Sekikawa.
主刀醫生，關川
Understood.
是
First assistant, Kakitani.
第一助手垣谷
Second assistant…
第二助手
Sera.
世良
-What? -Dr. Sera?
-什麼？ -世良醫生？
Really?
真的嗎？
Your answer?
回答我
Understood.
是
You may have your opinions,
你們可以有自己的想法
but we won't accept failure at Tojo University.
但東城大學的手術不允許失敗
The selected members will begin the preparation for surgery tomorrow.
獲選的成員請從明天開始做術前準備
That's all.
就這樣
Dr. Kurosaki, please wait.
黑崎醫生，請稍等一下
Why me?
為什麼要選我？
It's your patient, right?
那是你負責的患者吧？
And being the one Dr. Saeki selected,
而且你還被佐伯教授欽點
we can't leave you out.
不能不讓你參加
Think of it as training.
就當是訓練吧
In three days, we will perform a Snipe surgery.
三天後要進行的醫狙手術
The operating nurse will be Nekota.
手術室護士是貓田護士
I will also ask Miyamoto and Hanabusa.
還有宮元護士和花房護士
You newcomers need real-world experience.
你們新人需要累積實戰經驗
Listen and learn from your superiors.
和前輩多多學習吧
-Yes, ma'am. -Yes.
-是
Got it, Nekota?
可以吧，貓田護士？
Nekota?
貓田？
I know where she is.
一定又去那裡了
Excuse me.
打擾了
I think Nekota is in here…
貓田護士好像在這裡…
Nekota.
貓田
Nurse Fujiwara is looking for you.
藤原護士長在找你
She wants you on the Snipe surgery team.
她要你加入這次的醫狙手術小組
I came here to tell you about it.
我是來通知你的
The next day, the team was assembled
隔天手術組成員集合
and the lectures began.
開始聆聽講解
Upon hitting the mitral valve,
到了二尖瓣後
return this lever to its original position.
記得把栓子推回來
Then, just pull the trigger.
最後壓下手把
That's it.
這樣就完成了
It really is easy.
真的很簡單
That is the entire process.
以上就是整個流程
Dr. Sekikawa, from the top.
那請關川醫生重頭做一遍
Right.
好的
About Nekota…
關於貓田護士…
She only ever works with Dr. Tokai…
她只和渡海醫生配合手術…
You should avoid interacting with her.
最好別跟她來往比較好
What?
什麼？
I heard that tons of nurses have quit because of her.
聽說很多護士因為貓田護士而辭職
They call her the female Dr. Tokai.
大家都叫她女版渡海醫生
Push the catheter control button
按下導管操作按鈕
and advance the catheter to the mitral valve.
將導管伸入二尖瓣
Upon hitting the mitral valve,
到了二尖瓣以後
return the lever to its original position.
把栓子推回原先的位置
This is a hospital.
這裡是醫院
Your shift is over, right?
你的值班時間結束了吧？
I just finished mine too.
我也剛剛結束
Please…
麻煩…
take me off the operating team.
把我從手術小組撤除
Giving up on being a surgeon?
你要放棄當外科醫生嗎？
I…
我…
I almost killed Mr. Koyama.
我差點害死小山先生
It was the same with Ms. Minagawa.
皆川女士那時也是一樣
When I become a surgeon,
要是我這種人成了外科醫生
I might actually kill someone.
可能真的會害死人
This is the number of people
這是我至今為止
I've killed during surgery.
在手術過程中的致死的人數
But you, with your hands still clean,
但現在雙手還乾乾淨淨的你
you plan to back out?
居然打算放棄？
I find that incredibly irresponsible.
這也太不負責任了
Irresponsible?
不負責任？
I can still remember
我到現在都還記得
each one of their faces.
每一位患者的臉
Not a day has gone by that it doesn't hurt me.
沒有一天不為此心痛悔恨
The only thing left for me to do
我唯一所能做的
is to save hundreds and thousands more lives instead.
就是去拯救成千上萬條命作為彌補
You will become a surgeon too
你今後也會成為外科醫生
and save hundreds and thousands of lives.
去拯救幾百、幾千人的性命
If you quit now,
如果現在放棄的話
it wouldn't be any different than throwing away
就等於對幾千條人命
thousands of precious lives.
見死不救
You have one life to live
你只來這個人世間走一遭
and it's your duty to become a surgeon.
你的義務就是成為外科醫生
You must not run away from it.
不能逃避
I hear all of your pupils give up and quit on you.
我聽說跟著你的實習醫生都辭職了
It's true that your skill does save lives,
你的醫術確實能救活患者
but it kills doctors.
但卻扼殺了醫生
Just what are you trying to do?
你到底想達到什麼目的？
Doctors with bright futures, hoping to save lives.
那些未來可能救死扶傷的醫生
-You killed them. -No, no.
-都被你扼殺了 -錯了
It's the patients who would have been killed by those doctors.
那些本來可能被醫生害死的病患
That's who I'm trying to save.
都被我拯救了
Truly skilled doctors
真正醫術了得的醫生
can do whatever they want.
無論做什麼都會被原諒
Unskilled doctors…
醫術差勁的醫生…
are better off dead.
還是死了算了
You and I are polar opposites.
你跟我是兩個世界的人
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Would you like to make a bet?
要打個賭嗎？
Will Dr. Sera quit or not?
賭世良醫生會不會辭職
I don't bet on cheap odds.
我的賭注都很大喔
One hundred million.
一千萬日圓
Both of our severance payments.
賭我們各自的離職金
I believe he has a future.
我看好他的未來
How about you?
你認為呢？
The staff worked tirelessly
團隊成員不眠不休練習
preparing for the Snipe surgery.
為了醫狙的手術做準備
Passed the left ventricle.
已穿過左心室
And I continued to wonder
而我還是一直質疑
if I really had the qualifications to be there.
自己是否有資格待在這裡
Now, entering the mitral valve.
現在要進入二尖瓣了
Dr. Sekikawa?
關川醫生？
Yes, no problem.
我沒事
I will now insert the prosthesis.
現在置入人工心臟瓣膜
Finished.
完成
Next time, it will be the real thing.
下次就要真正做手術了
Let's do our best.
拿出我們的最佳表現吧
Mr. Koyama's condition stabilized,
小山先生的狀況很穩定
and his surgery was scheduled for the next day.
已經安排了明天動手術
Excuse me.
打擾了
Did you need me?
請問您找我嗎？
-Give this to the nurses. -Okay.
-把這個交給護士 -好的
Pardon me.
我先走了
And one more thing.
還有一件事
Yes?
是的？
TRAINING RELOCATION REQUEST FORM
（更換實習醫院申請書）
You forgot to write the reason.
你忘了寫理由
-It's incomplete. -Why do you have that?
-資料不完整 -怎麼會在您那裡？
Write it now.
現在就寫
I'll sign it for you.
我會幫你簽
Write it.
寫啊
Fine.
寫就寫
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
How many patients have you killed in surgery?
到目前為止 您有多少病人在手術台上喪命？
I know how skilled you are.
我知道您的醫術高明
But I…
但是我…
I can't treat lives as mere things the way you do.
我無法像您一樣 把患者的生命視若玩物
Dealing with human life…
跟人命打交道…
I'm scared. Life is fragile.
我很害怕，因為生命是如此脆弱
Is that wrong?
我說錯了嗎？
Zero.
一個也沒有
I have never…
我從來都沒有
killed a single patient.
害死過一個病人
If it's really so scary that it makes you cry,
如果你真的怕到忍不住哭出來
don't waste your time with relocation.
那也別浪費時間調職了
Just quit.
直接辭職吧
And get out.
省得礙事
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
You're still here?
您還沒回去啊？
Yes.
對
I just can't relax.
我還是很緊張
"Practice makes perfect."
“熟能生巧”
Those are nice words.
這句話說得真好
But practice isn't everything.
但光熟練根本無濟於事
If it doesn't help you win the game,
如果在比賽中不能發揮作用
it's meaningless.
那就毫無意義
Dr. Tokai said that surgery is like gambling.
渡海醫生把手術比喻成賭博
If that's true,
如果真的是這樣
I'm the guy who keeps losing the game.
那我就是逢賭必輸的人
I can't take this anymore…
我已經撐不下去了…
Then why don't you quit?
那為什麼不辭職算了？
Nekota…
貓田護士…
You think you're the one who's the most afraid?
你不會以為自己是最害怕的人吧？
You caught me off guard.
你來得真突然
You're here late.
您這麼晚了還在這裡
I'm not allowed in the operating room tomorrow,
因為我不能參加明天的手術
so I thought I would do what I can before I go.
所以下班前我要提前做好準備工作
It's like being a newbie doctor.
就像新手醫生一樣
Tomorrow,
明天
Japanese medicine will change forever.
日本的醫療史將徹底轉變
Thanks to the Snipe.
多虧了醫狙這項工具
It has been a while.
好久不見
I've been so busy.
我最近很忙
Playing nice with the professors while also helping Teika.
我想也是，一邊跟教授們套交情 同時協助帝華大學的業務
No wonder you're busy.
難怪你很忙
I'm only trying to help everyone.
我只是在幫大家的忙
I enjoy working with the best in class.
我喜歡接觸頂尖的事物
The Snipe is undoubtedly a top-class medical device.
醫狙無疑是一流的醫療器械
Dr. Saeki is of course a top-class surgeon.
佐伯醫生也是一流的外科醫生
And of course,
當然
your skills are, too.
渡海醫生您的醫術也是一流的
Would you like to observe the operation with me tomorrow?
您明天也跟我一起來參觀手術吧
I would like to hear your opinion.
我也想聽取您一流的意見
Dr. Takashina will be out of here tomorrow.
明天高階醫生就會離開這裡
Perhaps, I made the wrong choice?
那可能是我的選擇錯了吧？
See you.
我先走了
TRAINING RELOCATION REQUEST FORM
（更換實習醫院申請書）
If it's really so scary that it makes you cry,
如果你真的怕到忍不住哭出來
don't waste your time with relocation.
那也別浪費時間調職了
Just quit.
直接辭職吧
Why did I want to become a doctor?
我是為什麼想要當醫生呢？
Doctor…
所謂醫生…
What even is a doctor?
又是什麼呢？
Finally, the fateful day arrived.
就這樣，關鍵性的一天到了
Please wait in the waiting room until the operation is finished.
手術結束之前，請您在休息室等待
Oh, dear.
老公
Cut it out. What kind of face is that?
好了，那是什麼表情？
It's no big deal.
沒什麼大不了的
The doctor says it will be over in no time.
醫生說很快就會完成
I know, but…
我知道，但…
Don't worry.
別擔心
When we get out of here,
等我出院了
we'll take that money
就用拿到的補償金
and take everyone out to eat yakiniku.
帶大家去吃燒肉
How can you say that at a time like this?
都這時候了你怎麼還說這個？
You think you're the one who's the most afraid?
你不會以為自己是最害怕的人吧？
There's nothing to worry about.
都說了不用擔心
Right, doctor?
對吧，醫生？
It will be okay.
您放心吧
See? Well, here I go.
你看吧，那我要走了
-Bring him in. -Okay.
-麻煩你了 -好
I never thought Dr. Sekikawa would do this kind of operation.
沒想到關川醫生 能掌握這種二尖瓣手術
If this succeeds,
如果這次手術成功
does that mean we'll all start using the Snipe?
今後我們也可以開始操作醫狙吧？
If that happened…
如果真是那樣的話…
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生
Unskilled doctors
醫術差勁的醫生
will be performing surgery.
也可以做手術了
-Professor Saeki. -What are you all doing here?
-佐伯教授 -你們怎麼都在這裡？
This is no time to relax. Get to work!
現在不是休息的時候，快回去工作！
-Sorry! -Yes, sir.
-非常抱歉 -是
Tokai, why are you here?
渡海，你怎麼在這裡？
To observe?
來觀摩嗎？
No.
不是
I wanted to see you walk out.
我想親眼看到你離開
Thought I would give you my best.
所以來這裡跟你打個招呼
Your attention, please.
請你好好看著吧
What you're about to watch
接下來的景象
is the future I've been dreaming of.
就是我夢寐以求的未來
It's about to begin.
馬上要開始了
We'll now begin the on-pump mitral valve surgery with the Snipe.
接下來開始使用醫狙進行 體外循環二尖瓣手術
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir.
-拜託各位了 -請多指教
Scalpel.
手術刀
Electroscalpel.
電刀
You seem nervous.
你好像有點緊張
It's not my style.
這不是我平常的作風
Sitting still while everyone else works.
大家都在工作的時候，我卻在乾坐著
That will be an issue when you become a professor.
等你當上教授，如果還這樣會有問題
Would you make me a professor?
我能升到教授嗎？
It will depend on how hard you work.
這要看你日後的努力了
-Snipe. -Here.
-醫狙 -這裡
-He's sweating. -Right.
-擦汗 -好的
Pardon me.
不好意思
All right.
好了
Time to insert the Snipe.
終於來到插入醫狙這一步了
Inserting the Snipe.
插入醫狙
Smooth sailing.
很順利
Now, through the left ventricle.
然後慢慢通過左心室
We're through the left ventricle.
通過左心室了
Just like we practiced.
和練習的時候一樣
Next is the papillary muscle level.
接下來通過乳突肌
Through the papillary muscle.
通過乳突肌
Good.
很好
The final step.
最後一步
We've reached the mitral valve.
到達二尖瓣
We'll apply the prosthesis.
接下來置入人工心臟瓣膜
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I don't know. Something is stuck.
不知道，好像有什麼東西卡住了
Did you apply prosthesis?
你放入人工心臟瓣膜了嗎？
I'll try to remove it.
我試著先拔出來
Take it easy.
慢一點
The artificial valves have been dislodged!
人工心臟瓣膜脫落了
Why?
怎麼會？
Migration. What do we do?
移位了，該怎麼辦？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
What happened?
出什麼事了？
I don't know. The valves were dislodged.
不知道，人工心臟瓣膜突然脫落了
How?
怎麼會這樣？
They were released at an unexpected angle.
人工心臟瓣膜 在非預期內的角度推出去
Perhaps the problem was caused
也許問題出在
by the doctor quickly switching the Snipe into his dominant hand.
醫生很快把醫狙器械換到慣用手
But why would he do that?
但他為什麼要換手？
Dr. Sekikawa is left-handed.
關川醫生是左撇子
Don't forget to switch the lever back.
記得把栓子推回來
It's his first Snipe surgery.
這是他第一次用醫狙進行手術
His nerves got the best of him.
他被自己的緊張情緒壓垮了
Whenever Dr. Sekikawa performs difficult operations,
關川在進行難度高的手術時
Dr. Tokai is always there to take over for him.
往往都是渡海醫生代替他主刀
That means this is a human error.
表示這是人為造成的失誤
-Blood pressure dropping! -More fluid!
-血壓下降了 -快點輸液
-We need saline and albumin! -Right away!
-還需要白蛋白！ -馬上來
Let's call Dr. Takashina.
把高階醫生叫來吧
Dr. Takashina!
高階醫生
Wait.
等等
If you leave now…
如果你現在離開…
you'll never get to use that toy of yours again.
以後就別想再用那玩意了
Follow the manual.
按照說明書
Use the retrieval device and locate the valve.
用回收裝置回收脫落的人工心臟瓣膜
-Right. Prepare the retrieval device! -Okay!
-是，準備回收人工心臟瓣膜的裝置 -好
At this point, we better remove the Snipe.
都到這個地步了，還是先抽回醫狙吧
Dr. Sekikawa.
關川醫生
The professor is watching you.
教授正在看
If we don't get this right…
要是我們搞砸了…
We have to fix this!
一定要設法補救！
Damn it.
可惡！
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Dr. Takashina, are you watching?
高階醫生，您在看嗎？
We need help. Please help us.
我們需要幫助，您能來一趟嗎？
-Stop it, Dr. Sera! -Dr. Takashina!
-世良，別喊了 -高階醫生
The professor gave him the order.
教授已經下指示了
Dr. Takashina won't come.
高階醫生不會來的
We'll solve this ourselves!
我們只能靠自己了！
Hey.
喂！
Hey, Sera!
喂，世良！
-Sera. -Dr. Takashina.
-世良 -高階醫生
We need you.
我們需要你
We need your help.
我們需要你的幫助
Please.
拜託您了
Somewhere down the line, in this future of yours,
往後，在你夢寐以求的未來中
this problem will happen again.
類似的問題還會發生
When it does,
每次出狀況的時候
do you plan to run to the rescue?
你都打算趕過去救援嗎？
You said so.
我說過了
This is the reality of that dream of yours.
這就是你期待的未來
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
It's just as Professor Saeki says.
照佐伯教授說的做
Doctor…
醫生…
I vowed to take
我已經宣示過
full responsibility.
會全權負責
-Where's the retrieval device? -Two packs of saline.
-回收裝置還沒拿來嗎？ -再來兩袋白蛋白
Right!
是
-Get the heart-lung machine ready. -Right.
-準備好人工心肺機 -是
What are you doing? Go back.
你在幹什麼？回去
For the sake of the future.
我是為了未來才這麼做的
-Go back! -And you won't regret it?
-快回去 -您不會後悔嗎？
I don't want to regret it.
我不想後悔
The patient is fighting for his life.
病患正在掙扎求生
We must help him.
我們一定要救他
You told me yourself.
您自己也說過了
You can't walk away from a life in danger.
不可以逃避，見死不救
Dr. Takashina!
高階醫生！
You're the one who's running away!
真正逃避的人是你！
Why is this happening?
為什麼會這樣？
Hurry and take out the Snipe.
快點抽出器械
I brought the retrieval device.
回收裝置拿來了
Thank you.
謝謝
-Dr. Takashina. -Doctor…
-高階醫生 -醫生…
Forgive me.
請原諒我
Just focus on saving the patient.
現在專心救病人就好
Calm down.
冷靜下來
Follow the manual and retrieve the artificial valve.
按說明書 用回收裝置取出人工心臟瓣膜
-Retrieval device. -Here.
-回收裝置 -這裡
I'll take over.
我來接手
It appears they're on the right track.
看起來方法得當
Everything should be okay now, right?
這樣應該就沒問題了吧？
We'll see.
拭目以待吧
Almost at the artificial valve.
就到達人工心臟瓣膜處了
Blood pressure dropping!
血壓下降！
A hemorrhage in the left ventricle?
是左心室出血了嗎？
A hemorrhage…
出血了
The artificial valve has embedded itself and is tearing the muscle.
人工心臟瓣膜嵌入心肌，撕裂肌肉了
-Heart-lung machine! -Right!
-啟動人工心肺機 -是
-Bring the transfusion tubes. -Right.
-把輸血導管拿過來
-Transfusion!
-輸血 -是
-Guidewire. -Right.
-導線
Can they pull it off?
他們能處理嗎？
If they don't act soon, the patient will bleed out.
不馬上止血的話 病患會失血過多而死
-Dr. Sera, connect the veins. -Right.
-世良醫生，連接靜脈 -是
-Here you are. -What's happening?
-來了 -怎麼搞的？
If you don't hurry, the heart will tear.
不盡快取出，心臟會破裂
-You must retrieve it now. -I can't.
-快點取出來 -沒辦法
Be careful or the tissue will tear.
小心一點，否則心肌會撕裂
I'm trying to stop the bleeding.
我正在按壓止血
It won't hold!
但還是止不住
What should we do?
那該怎麼辦？
Oh, no. There's no time.
不行，快來不及了
Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生
Transfusion is no good.
輸血也沒有用
We can't do it…
我們束手無策了…
Damn it…
可惡…
Where's Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生呢？
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生…
I'll cover it up for ten million.
給我1000萬，我來搞定
Write your resignation letter.
所以你快去寫辭呈吧
Then I'll help you.
這樣我就幫你救
What are you saying? The artificial valve is stuck.
你怎麼救？人工心臟瓣膜卡在心肌裡
The patient is losing strength.
患者快要體力不支了
I can do it.
我能救他
-How? -Because it's me.
-怎麼救？ -我就是可以
We're losing blood!
還在失血！
Understood.
我知道了
Please go ahead.
那拜託你了
-Take it out! -Okay.
-抽出來 -是
-Heart-lung machine engaged.
-人工心肺正常運轉 -好
I'm going to sew him up.
我要縫合了
-Starting from the outside. Scalpel. -Here.
-直接從外面來，手術刀 -這裡
-Electroscalpel. -Okay.
-電刀 -是
-Suction.
-抽吸
-Running out of time. -Right.
-快來不及了 -是
-Thoracotomy device. -Yes, sir.
-胸廓切開器
-Two pieces of felt. -Okay.
-兩塊修補片 -是
-Forceps.
-鑷子 -好
All right. Four-zero.
好，4-0縫線
Hang in there, dear.
老公，加油
Hang in there!
加油啊
Metz.
手術剪
Repair complete.
修復完成
-He's so fast… -The valve extraction was the issue.
-好快… -問題是怎麼取出人工心臟瓣膜
One wrong move and the patient will die.
稍有差池，病患就會死亡
-Metz. -Okay.
-手術剪 -這裡
-Debakey. -Here.
-組織鑷
With a Debakey?
用組織鑷？
He plans on grabbing it directly?
他打算直接夾出來嗎？
Removing the valve like that…
用鑷子取出人工心臟瓣膜…
Can he see the entanglement just by looking at it?
他能看清楚卡住心肌的位置嗎？
Got it.
找到了
Okay. Removal complete.
好了，取出完成
Close it up.
縫合吧
Let's continue to the mitral valve.
繼續進行二尖瓣手術
What are you saying? The patient's heart is weak.
你說什麼？ 病人的心臟已經非常虛弱了
It's too dangerous to carry on.
繼續進行手術太危險
And whose fault is that?
那要怪誰？
Do you plan on closing him up?
你打算縫合嗎？
His heart will stop if you close it. He'll die.
縫上後他的心臟也不會跳，他會沒命
If we don't operate now, he'll die.
現在不做手術的話，他可就要死了
Brain monitor levels dropping.
腦部監測器的數值正在降低
There's no time. Only ten minutes until blood flow to the brain stops.
沒時間了，只剩下十分鐘
Let's do it on the beat.
那就在自主心跳下進行手術
At a time like this?
在這種情況下用佐伯式嗎？
The Saeki Method?
佐伯式？
-Let's open you up. Scalpel. -Here.
-來幫你開胸吧．手術刀 -這裡
-Broaden your field of view. -Right.
-擴大視野範圍 -好的
We have five minutes.
剩下五分鐘
-Five-zero. -Here.
-5-0縫線 -這裡
Only two minutes!
剩下兩分鐘
Repairing the valves under these conditions…
在這種情況下修復瓣膜…
Amazing.
太厲害了
Brain monitor level dropping!
腦部監測器的數值又下降了！
Less than one minute left!
還剩不到一分鐘
-Metz. -Here.
-手術剪 -這裡
Mitral valve repair complete.
二尖瓣修復完成
He did it…
他做到了
Dr. Tokai, what about the stitches?
渡海醫生，縫合呢？
You do it.
你來做
Right, doctor?
對吧，醫生？
It will be okay.
您放心吧
Okay.
是
-Dr. Sera, let me-- -I'll do it.
-世良，讓我… -我來縫
Thank you.
麻煩了
All right.
好了
Metz scissors, please.
請給我手術剪
Yes.
這裡
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Take out the forceps.
鬆開止血鉗
Okay.
是
Blood pressure…
血壓…
stabilized.
穩定了
Suturing complete.
縫合完成
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Well done, doctor.
醫生，您辛苦了
You too.
你也是
SCHEDULED FOR RECONSTRUCTION
（預定重建）
I apologize for the damage I have caused.
很抱歉給您添麻煩了
I disobeyed the professor's orders
我違背教授您的命令
and entered the operating room.
進入手術室
Professor Saeki,
難道佐伯教授
did you know this would happen?
您一開始就預料到這種情況嗎？
Even as technology advances,
不管科技再怎麼發達
there's always room for error when the human hand is involved.
永遠都會有人為失誤的空間
Everyone who is involved in medicine
從事醫療的每個人
must never forget this fact.
千萬不能忘記這一點
Everything is as I expected.
一切都在我的預料當中
There is nothing perfect in this world.
世上沒有完美的東西
Even so,
即便如此
I plan to make the Snipe the perfect tool.
我還是想把醫狙做到完美
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
I…
那個…
Are you really leaving our hospital?
您真的要離開我們醫院嗎？
It was Dr. Tokai who saved Mr. Koyama.
雖然最後救了小山先生的是渡海醫生
But if you hadn't been there,
但是如果沒有您
we couldn't have operated at all.
小山先生就根本不會接受手術
Forget about me.
別說我了
What about you?
你呢？
What?
什麼？
What do you plan to do?
你準備怎麼辦？
Going forward.
從今以後？
TRAINING RELOCATION REQUEST FORM
（更換實習醫院申請書）
I plan…
我打算…
to be prepared.
做好準備
Thank you.
謝謝
-What? -Are you ready, then?
-什麼？ -那你準備好了吧
-Huh? -Dr. Tokai?
渡海先生
We made a bet.
我們打了一個賭
Our resignation letters and severance pay.
賭注是辭呈和離職金
We bet on whether you would quit or not.
賭你會不會放棄當外科醫生
Dr. Tokai and I bet on this operation.
我跟渡海醫生賭上這次手術
But…
但是…
You ruined the whole thing.
你破壞了一切
What?
啊？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I'm glad you decided to stay, Dr. Sera.
我很高興你要留下來，世良醫生
That's not…
那不是…
Well, either way you'll be fired.
不管怎麼樣，你已經要被開除了
Fired?
-開除？ -你那樣公然地
Oh, no…
不是啊…
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦？
-You should hurry and go apologize. -Right!
-你趕快去道歉吧 -好
Oh, no.
慘了
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
I would like to thank you.
我想跟你道歉
You helped me find the Snipe's weak point.
你幫助我發現醫狙的缺點
You were just lucky this time.
這次算你狗屎運
You should get out of here.
你還是趕快辭職吧
When I finish my paper,
等我完成論文
and the Snipe is put into practical use,
醫狙也開始實際運用之後
you'll be the one who's out of here because all you have is skill.
要走的人會是你
You and I are truly polar opposites.
我跟你是不同世界的人
We cannot coexist in one place.
不可能在一個地方和平共存
Two sides of the same coin.
最終只能二擇一
Heads or tails, life or death.
正面還是反面，生還是死
Will it be me who leaves?
要走的人會是我
Or you?
還是你？
That's all there is.
最終就是這樣而已
What will become of that intern?
那個實習醫生會怎麼樣啊？
Intern?
實習醫生？
The one who disobeyed your orders and called for Dr. Takashina.
違背您的指令 擅自帶走高階醫生那一位
Pardon me.
打擾了
What?
怎麼會？
No one is here. What should I do?
沒人在，我該怎麼辦？
Who are you talking about?
你說的是誰？
Are we getting sushi tonight?
今晚是吃壽司嗎？
That's right.
是的
A three-star restaurant.
三星級餐廳
You know that there's only one route.
只有一條路可走
Touching the nerves could result in death.
碰觸到神經會導致病患喪命
Stick it in the mitral valve and pull the switch, right?
我們只需要進入瓣膜 縫合起來，對吧？
You have any problems with that?
有什麼問題嗎？
Don't mess with me!
別惹我！
If we fail…
要是我們失敗了…
The Snipe will be out of your hands completely.
你會徹底失去醫狙這項工具
We're friends, not enemies.
我們是朋友，不是敵人
-We need assistance! -Dear!
-這裡需要協助！ -老公！
Who will you save? Who will you kill?
誰生或誰死，你怎麼決定？
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：莊雅婷